# FARID MUSA



# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:

Python, C++, MASM

Databases

MySQL, SQLite, HDF5

Web Development:

PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS,

JQuery

Statistical tools: R, Pandas, NumPy, scikit-learn, matplotlib

Engineering Software: MATLAB, Aspen Plus, Polymath, Excel

Operating Systems:
Debian, OpenSuSE, Windows
Word Processors:
TeX, MS Word
Graphic Design:
PowerPoint, Photoshop, Illustrator

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Analyst and Critical-thinker
Creative thinking
Strong computer competency
Good communication skills
Teamwork Skills (Reliability/Tolerance)

Docendo discimus

#### CONTACT

Yaka Mah., Altıntaş Sok. No 41 Daire 19 Urla/Izmir, 35430

+90 539 387 60 80

farid.musa.h@gmail.com

mmtechslv.github.io

linkedin.com/in/faridmusa github.com/mmtechslv

#### **PROFILE**

With a bachelor's degree in chemical engineering, a master degree in biotechnology and solid experience in various fields like web-development, database design, mathematical modeling and simulation, bioinformatic pipeline design and data analysis; I have built mixed set of skills that aid me in understanding of interdisciplinary problems. Motivated and passionate about health informatics, bioinformatic, data science and software development.

# **WORK HISTORY**

#### **INTERN**

Sanem Plastik | Nov 2017 - Dec 2017

#### INTEDN

Bareks Plastik | Jul 2017 - Aug 2017

# FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Freelance | Jan 2012 - Jan 2017

Worked as freelance web developer using PHP-MySQL for back-end and HTML5/CSS3/JScript for front-end.

#### **WEB DEVELOPER**

Samur Medya Digital Agency | Jun 2016 - Oct 2016

Worked as a turnkey web developer.

#### **WEB DEVELOPER**

Webtali İş Geliştirme Ajansı | Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Developed Customer Relationship Management (CRM) web application for the agency.

#### **FREELANCE TRANSLATOR**

Zemexpert Tourism Agency | Jun 2014 - Jan 2015

Worked as a freelance translator of English, Russian and Turkish languages.

# **EDUCATION**

# MS, BIOTECHNOLOGY AND BIOENGINEERING

Izmir Institute of Technology | 2018 - 2020

PhyloMAF - NEXT GENERATION PHYLOGENETIC MICROBIOME ANALYSIS FRAMEWORK (Ongoing)

 Key-points: address shortcomings of the microbiome field, contribute to microbiome research community

BIOINFORMATIC ANALYSIS AND BIO-STATISTICAL MODELLING OF GENETIC INTERACTIONS BETWEEN MICROBIOTA AND HOST (MS Thesis, Ongoing)

• Description: Investigate host-microbiota interactions "Drosophila Genetic Reference Panel" samples using micoribome-GWAS techniques.

# LANGUAGES

Azerbaijani: Native Russian: Native Turkish: Fluent English: Advanced

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BS. CHEMICAL ENGINEERING**

Izmir Institute of Technology | 2011 - 2017

ENGINEERING DESIGN AND ECONOMICS: PRODUCTION OF DIMETHYL ETHER (DME) FROM NATURAL GAS

• Key-points: market analysis, mathematical modeling, automated Aspen Plus process simulations and optimization via MATLAB.

DESIGN AND SYNTHESIS OF NANO DRUG DELIVERY VEHICLES (BS Thesis)

• Description: The project involved preparation and characterization of cytotoxic anti-cancer liposome agents loaded with different alkaline solutions.

# **CONFERENCE PARTICIPATION**

#### **UKMK-2016**

INTERNATIONAL CHEMICAL ENGINEERING CONGRESS | 2016

#### Poster presentation

• Project Title: PANCAR - AN INNOVATIVE APPROACH TOWARDS A WEARABLE ARTIFICIAL PANCREAS

#### **HIBIT-2018**

INTERNATIONAL SYMPOSIUM ON HEALTH INFORMATICS AND BIOINFORMATICS | 2018

#### **HIBIT-2019**

INTERNATIONAL SYMPOSIUM ON HEALTH INFORMATICS AND BIOINFORMATICS | 2019

#### Poster presentation

 Project Title: PhyloMAF - NEXT GENERATION PHYLOGENETIC MICROBIOME ANALYSIS FRAMEWORK

#### TRAINING AND COURSES

#### **EVOLUTIONARY GENOMICS APPLIED WORKSHOP**

ECOEVO | Winter 2018

In three days and in team of three people developed bioinformatic pipeline for processing and analysis of raw NGS yeast genome reads.

# AEGEAN SEMINARS FOR COMPUTATIONAL ECOLOGY AND EVOLUTION

ECOEVO | Fall 2017

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

#### **WORK AND TRAVEL USA**

Summer 2015

#### REFERENCES

References available upon request.